

Martin Hernandez

Full Stack Developer

Email martinl11dev@outlook.com
Address Braunschweig, Germany
Phone +49 5341 8139 706

OBJECTIVE

Proactive and reliable full-stack engineer with a broad web application development skill set. Has been working on various products and clients, from solving enterprisegrade problems to launching new applications for startups. Involves leading technical teams by creating an accessible development environment, fixing technical debts, enforcing best practices in teams, and mentoring developers.

EXPERIENCE

Nifti.com *Apr 2017 - May 2018*

Front-end Engineer

- Created reusable D3.js charts using Raphael.js to draw SVG on browsers.
- Handled responsive design layouts for views.
- Implemented reusable components for UX using jQuery.
- Created an xQuery Selector generator from an HTML Element DOMNode.
- Created a Pop CSS editor for elements.

WhoaStork May 2020 - Jul 2021

Front-end Engineer

- Created the admin application of the web store in React
- Replaced Redux with Apollo Client for GraphQL against a Ruby back-end.
- Created a HOC architecture to reuse common GraphQL functionality for listing and filtering.
- Created our own custom UI library with styled components.
- Used HOC for form manipulation.

Globa.li

Nov 2018 - Feb 2020

Full-stack JavaScript Engineer

- Created a new front-end app based on React and Redux.
- Added a Hot module replacement plugin to Webpack.
- Worked with legacy code on the server side, able to understand the principles behind it and make it work again.

luckycloud.de May 2021 - Sep 2023

Full Stack Developer

- Led the redesign of the entire React.js frontend to align with updated design standards
- Implemented new features, resolved bugs in the backend, and achieved a 15% performance boost through strategic workflow and structural optimizations
- Successfully built 15+ server APIs for enhanced web and desktop application communication
- Improved application performance by 25% by implementing caching techniques and optimizing SQL queries
- Contributed to the "Seafile-Haiwen" open-source project

EDUCATION

Braunschweig, Germany Jun 2012 - Apr 2016

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Technical University of Braunschweig

Advanced Computer Architecture

SKILLS

- Web Development
- Effective Communication
- Project Management Professional Certification
- Project Management Software
- Software Development Life Cycle
- Agile (Scrum) methodologies
- Problem solving
- Planning

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Increased sales revenue by 20% within six months through effective marketing strategies
- $\bullet \ \ Led\ a\ cross-functional\ team\ to\ successfully\ launch\ a\ new\ product,\ resulting\ in\ a\ 30\%\ increase\ in\ market\ share.$

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

AWS Certified Developer

Amazon Web Services

LANGUAGES

German Native English Advanced